<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts | Sevan Harput</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
      <atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Posts</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>©2019-{currentYear} by Sevan Harput</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 14:03:47 +1000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/img/SPE3D_Ultrasound_Lab_logoSR_long.png</url>
      <title>Posts</title>
      <link>/post/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presenting our research at Westminster, London, UK.</title>
      <link>/post/jan2020_stemforbritain/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 14:03:47 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/jan2020_stemforbritain/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dr Harput has been selected to display his research as a poster at the House of Commons on Monday 9th March in the Engineering Sciences Session of &lt;a href=&#34;http://stemforbritain.org.uk/&#34;&gt;STEM for BRITAIN 2020&lt;/a&gt;, from 3.30pm – 6.15pm in the Attlee Suite, Portcullis House, London, UK.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sevan gave a seminar on 4 February 2020 at the Institute of Cancer Research (ICR), London, UK.</title>
      <link>/post/jan2020_icr-seminar/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 14:03:47 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/jan2020_icr-seminar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dr Harput is invited to give a seminar on ‘Super-Resolution Ultrasound Imaging with Microbubble Contrast Agents: Challenges and Opportunities’ at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.icr.ac.uk/&#34;&gt;Institute of Cancer Research (ICR)&lt;/a&gt;, London, UK.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr Harput is invited to the ‘Leaders in Innovation Fellowship’ networking event, London, UK.</title>
      <link>/post/jan2020_raeng_networkingevent/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 14:03:47 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/jan2020_raeng_networkingevent/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dr Harput has been invitated by Ambassador Ümit Yalçın, for “Leaders in Innovation Fellowship” networking event that he will be hosting on Tuesday, 28th January 2020 at the Ambassadorial Residence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Leaders in Innovation Fellowships (LIF) programme, which is run by the Royal Academy of Engineering and supported by the Newton Fund, works with engineers, academics and researchers in 16 countries, who have an innovation that could have a positive social or economic impact in their own countries or other developing nations. 15 participants from each country are chosen to attend an intensive 2-week entrepreneurship training course in London followed by up to a year of one-to-one support in their home countries to build their capacity to bring their innovations to market. There is a global community of over a thousand innovators working across a wide range of engineering disciplines and sectors tackling complex global challenges, including medical technology, agrotechnology and food security, water and sanitation, sustainable energy, and data infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minister of Education (United Arab Emirates) and Executive Vice President (Khalifa University) visited LSBU.</title>
      <link>/post/jan2020_uae_minister_of_education/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2020 14:03:47 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/jan2020_uae_minister_of_education/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dr Harput and Dr Grisan presented thier ultrasound imaging project to HE. Hussein Bin Ibrahim Al Hammadi (Minister of Education, UAE Ministry of Education), Dr. Arif Sultan Al Hammadi (Executive Vice President, Khalifa University) and Dr. Samuel Sheng Mao Senior Director, Masdar Institute/Khalifa University.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our abstract has been accepted for the 25th European symposium on Ultrasound Contrast Imaging 2020 in Rotterdam, NL.</title>
      <link>/post/dec2019_rotterdam_conf_accept/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 14:03:47 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/dec2019_rotterdam_conf_accept/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our abstract on ‘Micro vessel Analysis with 3D Super-resolution Ultrasound and Super-Resolved Velocity Mapping’ has been accepted as an oral presentation for the competition: SUPER-RESOLUTION IMAGING. 
It will be presented by Matthieu Toulemonde at the 25th European symposium on Ultrasound Contrast Imaging 2020 in Rotterdam, NL.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apply for a PhD in ultrasound imaging.</title>
      <link>/post/nov2019_phd_positions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 14:03:47 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/nov2019_phd_positions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PhD scholarships available in ultrasound imaging: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jobs.ac.uk/job/BWO083/phd-scholarships&#34;&gt;https://www.jobs.ac.uk/job/BWO083/phd-scholarships&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lsbu.ac.uk/__data/assets/pdf_file/0011/254756/Advert-PhD-SoE_Nov2019.pdf&#34;&gt;Click here&lt;/a&gt; for more details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sevan attends IEEE International Ultrasonics Symposium (IUS) 2019 in Glasgow, UK.</title>
      <link>/post/oct2019_ius/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2019 14:03:47 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/oct2019_ius/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Catching up with friends and colleagues in Glasgow, UK.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sevan joins London South Bank University as a lecturer</title>
      <link>/post/july2019_lsbu_start/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2019 14:03:47 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/july2019_lsbu_start/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is a very friendly environment. Many opportunities to start and lead new research projects.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sevan&#39;s leaving do at Imperial College London</title>
      <link>/post/july2019_imperial_leaving/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2019 14:03:47 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/july2019_imperial_leaving/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Thank you everyone for coming. I will remember it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
