<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts | Sevan Harput</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
      <atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Posts</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>©2019-{currentYear} by Sevan Harput</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2024 14:33:17 +1000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/img/SPE3D_Ultrasound_Lab_logoSR_long.png</url>
      <title>Posts</title>
      <link>/post/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our featured article on Applied Physics Letters is being noticed.</title>
      <link>/post/2024aug_apl_downloads/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2024 14:33:17 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2024aug_apl_downloads/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This article was publised as a part of the special issue on Fundamentals and Applications of Metamaterials: Breaking the Limits.
&lt;br&gt;
Read our research article &lt;a href=&#34;https://pubs.aip.org/aip/apl/article-abstract/123/8/082203/2907915/A-human-ear-inspired-ultrasonic-transducer-HEUT&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Congratulations to Hossam Hassan Sultan for successfully defending his PhD!</title>
      <link>/post/2024july_hossam_viva/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2024 10:01:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2024july_hossam_viva/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After answering three hours of questions from Prof Steven Freear (external examiner) and Prof Perry Xiao (internal examiner) on ultrasound, cortical bone and data processing, Hossam Hassan Sultan passed his PhD examination.
Thank you to both examiners and special thanks to Prof Mohammad Ghavami for chairing the examination.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fulfilling meeting between LSBU &amp; Medeniyet University.</title>
      <link>/post/2024june_medeniyet-uni-meeting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 14:01:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2024june_medeniyet-uni-meeting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Great opportunity to talk to colleagues and researchers from Turkey about our knowledge exchange activities.
Special thanks to Prof Arafat Salih Aydiner (Management Information Systems at Medeniyet University) and Furkan Karayaka (Board Member of Istanbul Medeniyet TechnoPark and Vice Chair of the Investment Office of the Presidency of the Republic of Turkiye).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our research presentation at ISMICT conference 2024, London, UK.</title>
      <link>/post/2024may_ismict-conf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 10:01:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2024may_ismict-conf/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Great presentation by Hossam Hassan Sultan on exploring the role of ultrasound signals, envelope features with the application of machine learning algorithms for bone health monitoring.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our research presentation at the National Physical Laboratory (NPL) SNM seminar 2024 in London, UK.</title>
      <link>/post/2024apr_npl_snm_seminar/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 10:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2024apr_npl_snm_seminar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Great presentation by Mishal Alfadhly on development of a new non-contact ultrasonic/acoustic pressure detection method for the nuclear industry.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Journal article on bone characterisation using ultrafast ultrasound.</title>
      <link>/post/2024mar_ieee_access/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 14:33:17 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2024mar_ieee_access/</guid>
      <description>&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read our research article &lt;a href=&#34;https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/10537175&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New research grant awarded by the MRC.</title>
      <link>/post/2024jan_mrc_grant/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 14:03:47 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2024jan_mrc_grant/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Speed Ultrasound Lab won a new research grant, funded by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ukri.org/councils/mrc/&#34;&gt;the Medical Research Council (MRC)&lt;/a&gt; to develop new drug delivery technology to the brain.
The problem with cancer drugs, or chemotherapy in general, is that drugs kill the health tissue along with the tumour. Our technology, which is a combination of microwaves and ultrasound, will be able to activate the cancer drugs on demand, only at desired locations inside the brain to minimize the collateral damage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A total of £155.9k is awarded for this research project ‘&lt;a href=&#34;/lab/#funding&#34;&gt;Enhancing Blood-Brain Barrier Opening with Ultrasound and Microwaves for Targeted Drug Delivery&lt;/a&gt;’.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr Harput joins the editorial board of the Frontiers in Acoustics.</title>
      <link>/post/2023nov_frontierseditor/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 14:33:17 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2023nov_frontierseditor/</guid>
      <description>&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pleased to join the editorial board of Frontiers in Acoustics as review editor. This new journal will help drive innovation in its field through high quality open access research. Find out more:
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.frontiersin.org/journals/acoustics&#34;&gt;https://www.frontiersin.org/journals/acoustics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A very busy week at LSBU.</title>
      <link>/post/2023sept_lsbu_welcome_week/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2023 14:33:17 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2023sept_lsbu_welcome_week/</guid>
      <description>&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is the welcome week at LSBU. Students are back.
Dr Harput&amp;rsquo;s and Jerome Grave&amp;rsquo;s research are showcased during the Welcome Week.
Kudos to Dr Safia Barikzai for the photos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three presentations and more at the IEEE IUS 2023 in Montreal, Canada.</title>
      <link>/post/2023sept_ius2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Sep 2023 14:33:17 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2023sept_ius2023/</guid>
      <description>&lt;html&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Hossam H. Sultan et al. – “Cortical Bone Thickness Assessment from Multi-frequency Ultrasound RF Data using a Convolutional Architecture with Multi-head Attention”&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Jerome Graves et al. – “Determining the grain geometry from ultrasonic measurements of large-grained temperate ice cores”&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Mohammad Aldahi et al. – “Investigation of Ultrasonically Levitated Droplets for Sonochemistry with High-Speed Camera Observations
”&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the full IEEE IUS 2023 program &lt;a href=&#34;https://2023.ieee-ius.org/&#34;&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Featured article on Applied Physics Letters.</title>
      <link>/post/2023aug_apl_featured/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Aug 2023 14:33:17 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2023aug_apl_featured/</guid>
      <description>&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read our research article &lt;a href=&#34;https://pubs.aip.org/aip/apl/article-abstract/123/8/082203/2907915/A-human-ear-inspired-ultrasonic-transducer-HEUT&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Imaging fabella at the Royal Society Summer Science Exhibition.</title>
      <link>/post/2023july_rs_sse/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2023 18:00:00 +1300</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2023july_rs_sse/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It was an amazing experience to attend the Royal Society Summer Science Exhibition and do ultrasound scans on 147 volunteers, including two Fellows of the Royal Society and many science enthusiasts. Special thanks to Dr Michael Berthaume for leading the exhibition and Mrs Fenja Deister for her invaluable work.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you know how many researchers work on ultrasound in south London?</title>
      <link>/post/2023may_slug/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 18:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2023may_slug/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A social event for ultrasound researchers in south London - all postcodes starting with an “S” :)
Professors, lecturers, PDRAs, PhDs and any researchers with or without a degree are all welcome.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our research presentation at Nuclear Decommissioning Authority (NDA) PhD bursary seminar 2023 in Manchester, UK.</title>
      <link>/post/2023jan_nda-seminar/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2023 10:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2023jan_nda-seminar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Great presentation by Mishal Alfadhly on development of a new non-contact ultrasonic/acoustic pressure detection method for the nuclear industry.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Congratulations to Luke Alderson for receiving the IET Future Talent Award.</title>
      <link>/post/2023jan_luke_iet-award/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 10:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2023jan_luke_iet-award/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Congratulations on receiving the IET Future Talent boost scholarship award! Our lab is so happy for you, and proud.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We are teaching ultrasound imaging for the world&#39;s first anthroengineeing course.</title>
      <link>/post/2022nov_ultrasound-in-anthroengineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2022 13:00:40 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2022nov_ultrasound-in-anthroengineering/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A completely new academic course, MSc Anthroengineering, which for the first time brings together Engineering (science of technology) and Anthropology (science of humanity) has been started. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lsbu.ac.uk/about-us/news/worlds-first-anthroengineering-academic-course-to-start-in-2022&#34;&gt;Click here for more&amp;hellip;&lt;/a&gt;.
Dr Harput is teaching the physics and applications of medical imaging modalities, especially ultrasound imaging.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Four presentations and more at the IEEE IUS 2022 in Venice, Italy.</title>
      <link>/post/2022oct_ius2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2022 14:33:17 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2022oct_ius2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;html&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Hossam H. Sultan et al. – “Estimation of Cortical Bone Strength Using CNN-based Regression Model”&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;br&gt; https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/9957568
&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Luzhen Nie et al. – “3D Localization of Scatterers with a Spiral-Shaped Acoustic Lens”&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;br&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/9958492&#34;&gt;https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/9958492&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Hossam H. Sultan et al. – “Classification of Cortical Bone Thicknesses Based on RF Signal Spectral Analysis”&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;br&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/9958573&#34;&gt;https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/9958573&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Ge Zhang et al. – “Ultrasound Super-Resolution Imaging for the Differentiation of Thyroid Nodules: A Feasibility Study”&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;br&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/9958286&#34;&gt;https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/9958286&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the full IUS 2022 program check the &lt;a href=&#34;https://2022.ieee-ius.org/&#34;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt; before the conference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab Transformation. Before and after.</title>
      <link>/post/2022aug_lab_transformation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 14:03:47 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2022aug_lab_transformation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New Ultrasound Research Lab is fully functional and operational at LSBU E217!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Four abstracts have been accepted for the IEEE IUS 2022.</title>
      <link>/post/2022june_ius2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2022 14:03:47 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2022june_ius2022/</guid>
      <description>&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the full IUS 2022 program check the &lt;a href=&#34;https://2022.ieee-ius.org/&#34;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt; before the conference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our research presentation at QMSKI 2022 in Noordwijk, Netherlands.</title>
      <link>/post/2022june_qmski/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2022 11:30:47 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2022june_qmski/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Great presentation by Hossam Hassan on detection of cortical bone porosity and thickness using multi-frequency ultrasound measurements at &lt;a href=&#34;https://qmski.org/&#34;&gt;QMSKI 2022&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fully Funded &amp; Industry Sponsored PhD Scholarship in Ultrasonic Testing and Data Analysis for Nuclear Industry</title>
      <link>/post/2022may_phd_positions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 14:03:47 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2022may_phd_positions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are offering an industrial PhD scholarships funded by the National Nuclear Laboratory and the Sellafield Ltd, which manages the nuclear fuel reprocessing, nuclear waste storage and nuclear decommissioning. The industrial partners expect the PhD project to develop into a real world product, where the successful PhD candidate will be able to lead the project beyond the PhD timeline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/file/d/1ANbsAeK9D8KZuszHk1e0bqP04NX-GYfx/view?usp=sharing&#34;&gt;Click here for details&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apply for a PhD in ultrasound and microwave dual-modality imaging.</title>
      <link>/post/2022apr_phd_positions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 14:13:47 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2022apr_phd_positions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PhD scholarships available in dual-modality cancer therapy with ultrasound and microwaves using nanodroplets.
The aim of this research project is to develop a novel therapeutic method by combining ultrasound and microwave imaging modalities to activate nanodroplets.
The PhD project will focus on characterization of novel therapeutic nanodroplets using ultrasound and microwaves. PhD student will work closely with the Prof M Thanou’s research team at King’s College London, who are developing the nanodroplets.
&lt;a href=&#34;https://drive.google.com/file/d/1l_0xaYC38muGHpGlYt8urqaxjWdDrYED/view?usp=sharing&#34;&gt;Click here for details&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Realistic Bone Simulations for Ultrasonic Characterization of Cortical Bone Porosity and Thickness</title>
      <link>/post/2022mar_realisticbonesim/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2022 12:03:47 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2022mar_realisticbonesim/</guid>
      <description>&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To establish a more realistic model, cortical bone simulations were generated using microstructural elements extracted from a real micrograph. Then, the new extracted pores have been used as seeds to build a reference dictionary. For the extracted pores, many features have been calculated and considered such as the effective diameters, pore sizes, and pores geometrical shapes. By employing this dictionary, numerous numbers of new cortical bone maps could be generated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In realsitic simulations, pores are randomly distributed within the cortical bone to mimic different biological conditions. In addition, geometric distortions have been added and considered including bone curvature, surface roughness, and pore-density weighting along the lateral-medial or anterior-posterior direction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Research project: ‘&lt;a href=&#34;/project/bone_characterization/&#34;&gt;Ultrasonic bone characterization&lt;/a&gt;’.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fully funded industrial PhD position available.</title>
      <link>/post/2021oct_phd_position/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2021 14:33:17 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2021oct_phd_position/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PhD scholarship available in Ultrasonic Non-Destructive Testing: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.findaphd.com/phds/program/phd-scholarship-in-ultrasonic-non-destructive-testing-for-nuclear-applications/?i152p5453&#34;&gt;https://www.findaphd.com/phds/program/phd-scholarship-in-ultrasonic-non-destructive-testing-for-nuclear-applications/?i152p5453&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The successful candidate will develop an ultrasonic analysis tool for detecting hydrogen gas in sealed pressurised storage containers. This project is fully funded by the National Nuclear Laboratory. The post will also offer a job opportunity in the nuclear sector at the end of the PhD period. Please contact Dr Sevan Harput by email for more details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three abstracts have been accepted for the IEEE IUS 2021.</title>
      <link>/post/2021sept_ius2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 14:03:47 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2021sept_ius2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;html&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Luzhen Nie et al. – “Localization of a Scatterer in 3D with a Single-Element Transducer”&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;br&gt; Session Code: MIS Coded Excitation &amp; Tomography (Poster)
&lt;br&gt; Date &amp; Time:  Thursday September 16, 2021 (10:15 - 12:15)
&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Mircea Constantin et al. – “Quantitative Microvessel Analysis with 3D Super-Resolution Ultrasound and Velocity Mapping”&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;br&gt; Session Code: PAT Acoustic Tweezers &amp;amp; Particle Manipulation I (Lecture)
&lt;br&gt; Date &amp;amp; Time: Monday September 13, 2021 (13:00 - 15:00)
&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Laura Peralta et al. – “Feasibility of 3D Coherent multi-Transducer Ultrasound Imaging with Two Sparse Arrays”&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;br&gt; Session Code: MBB Volumetric Beamforming &amp;amp; Imaging (Poster)
&lt;br&gt; Date &amp;amp; Time:  Wednesday September 15, 2021 (10:45 - 12:45)
&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the full IUS 2021 program &lt;a href=&#34;https://2021.ieee-ius.org/program-grid/&#34;&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Ultrasound Bone Quantification Project</title>
      <link>/post/2021june_rei-presentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 14:03:47 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2021june_rei-presentation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;html&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Sevan Harput – “A New Non-Invasive Technique for Bone Porosity Imaging”&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;br&gt; Event: BioMedical Imaging at LSBU: A Vision of the Future in Imaging Technology
&lt;br&gt; Organiser: London South Bank University
&lt;br&gt; Date &amp; Time:  June 8, 2021 (10:20)
&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; 
&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Join us to take the next step with your business and learn about the cutting edge developments in the area of BioMedical Imaging and Image Processing. The speakers will discuss successes in research, collaboration and commercialisation – in the areas of Ultrasound, Microwave Ultrawide Band Imaging, Infrared sensing and applications of machine vision and deep learning all to increase the quality of patient outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New 3D printed acoustic lenses for imaging</title>
      <link>/post/2021mar_3d-lenses/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 14:03:47 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2021mar_3d-lenses/</guid>
      <description>&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Desing and fabrication of our new acoustic lenses done for the our &lt;a href=&#34;https://royalsociety.org/&#34;&gt;the Royal Society&lt;/a&gt; research project ‘&lt;a href=&#34;/lab/#funding&#34;&gt;Human Ear-inspired Ultrasonic Transducer (HEUT) with a Spiral-shaped Acoustic Lens for 3D Localization of Sparse Scatterers&lt;/a&gt;’.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our paper is accepted to ISBI 2021.</title>
      <link>/post/2021feb_isbi2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 14:03:47 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2021feb_isbi2021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;html&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Enrico Grisan et al. – “Deep-Learning Estimation of Perfusion Kinetic Parameters in Contrast-Enhanced Ultrasound Imaging”&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;br&gt; Session: Poster session 4 
&lt;br&gt; Date &amp; Time:  April 15, 2021 (15:15)
&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; 
&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Proceedings paper is available here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/9433776&#34;&gt;IEEE Xplore&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://openresearch.lsbu.ac.uk/item/8vyzq&#34;&gt;LSBU Open Research&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LAB-in-a-BOX</title>
      <link>/post/2021jan_lab-in-a-box/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 14:03:47 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2021jan_lab-in-a-box/</guid>
      <description>&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We packed and shipped over 45 boxes for EEE students at level 6 and level 7. By using the LAB-in-a-BOX, it will be possible to do the labs from home and get real hands on experience during Covid.
Tweeted by the division, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/EEE_LSBU/status/1356728489714606080&#34;&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Six abstracts have been accepted for the IEEE IUS 2020.</title>
      <link>/post/2020sept_ius2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 14:03:47 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2020sept_ius2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;html&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Luzhen Nie et al. – “Localization of a Scatterer in 3D with a Single Measurement and Single Element Transducer”&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;br&gt; Session Code: B1P-24 (Poster)
&lt;br&gt; Date &amp; Time:  Wednesday September 09, 2020 (04:15 - 06:15)
&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Sevan Harput et al. – “Quantitative Microvessel Analysis with 3D Super-Resolution Ultrasound and Velocity Mapping”&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;br&gt; Session Code:            B5P-07 (Poster)
&lt;br&gt; Date &amp;amp; Time:              Wednesday September 09, 2020 (11:30 - 13:30)
&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Matthieu Toulemonde et al. – “3D Super Localized Flow with Locally and Acoustically Activated Nanodroplets and High Frame Rate Imaging Using a Matrix Array”&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;br&gt; Session Code:            B5P-11 (Poster)
&lt;br&gt; Date &amp;amp; Time:              Wednesday September 09, 2020 (11:30 - 13:30)
&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Ge Zhang et al. – “Effect of Contrast Agent Concentration in Bubble- and Droplet-Based Super-Resolution Imaging Using a Cardiac Phased Array Probe”&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;br&gt; Session Code:            B5P-07 (Poster)
&lt;br&gt; Date &amp;amp; Time:              Wednesday September 09, 2020 (11:30 - 13:30)
&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Ge Zhang et al. – “Effect of Mechanical Index on Repeated Sparse Activation of Nanodroplets in Vivo”&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;br&gt; Session Code:            B5P-11 (Poster)
&lt;br&gt; Date &amp;amp; Time:              Wednesday September 09, 2020 (11:30 - 13:30)
&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Michael Berthaume et al. – “Detecting and Characterizing the Fabella with High Frame-Rate Ultrasound Imaging”&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;br&gt; Session Code:            C1P-10 (Poster)
&lt;br&gt; Date &amp;amp; Time:               Thursday September 10, 2020 (04:15 - 06:15)
&lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/html&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the full IUS 2020 program &lt;a href=&#34;https://2020.ieee-ius.org/program-0&#34;&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apply for a PhD in ultrasound bone imaging.</title>
      <link>/post/2020july_phd_positions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 14:03:47 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2020july_phd_positions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PhD scholarships available in ultrasound bone imaging.
Contact Dr Harput for details. Application deadline is 01/08/2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presented at STEM for BRITAIN 2020</title>
      <link>/post/2020mar_stemforbritain/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Mar 2020 14:03:47 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2020mar_stemforbritain/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dr Harput has displayed his research as a poster at the House of Commons on Monday 9th March in the Engineering Sciences Session of &lt;a href=&#34;http://stemforbritain.org.uk/&#34;&gt;STEM for BRITAIN 2020&lt;/a&gt;, in the Attlee Suite, Portcullis House, London, UK.
Our work received press release and media coverage &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lsbu.ac.uk/about-us/news/new-research-grant-awarded-by-the-royal-society-and-presenting-at-stem-for-britain-2020&#34;&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New research grant awarded by the Royal Society.</title>
      <link>/post/2020mar_rs_grant/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2020 14:03:47 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2020mar_rs_grant/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Speed Ultrasound Lab won a new research grant by &lt;a href=&#34;https://royalsociety.org/&#34;&gt;the Royal Society&lt;/a&gt; to develop new ultrasound transducer technology.
A total of £20k is awarded for this research project ‘&lt;a href=&#34;/lab/#funding&#34;&gt;Human Ear-inspired Ultrasonic Transducer (HEUT) with a Spiral-shaped Acoustic Lens for 3D Localization of Sparse Scatterers&lt;/a&gt;’.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presenting our research at Westminster, London, UK.</title>
      <link>/post/2020jan_stemforbritain/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 14:03:47 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2020jan_stemforbritain/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dr Harput has been selected to display his research as a poster at the House of Commons on Monday 9th March in the Engineering Sciences Session of &lt;a href=&#34;http://stemforbritain.org.uk/&#34;&gt;STEM for BRITAIN 2020&lt;/a&gt;, from 3.30pm – 6.15pm in the Attlee Suite, Portcullis House, London, UK.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Seminar on 4 February 2020 at the Institute of Cancer Research (ICR), London, UK.</title>
      <link>/post/2020jan_icr-seminar/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 14:03:47 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2020jan_icr-seminar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dr Harput is invited to give a seminar on ‘Super-Resolution Ultrasound Imaging with Microbubble Contrast Agents: Challenges and Opportunities’ at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.icr.ac.uk/&#34;&gt;Institute of Cancer Research (ICR)&lt;/a&gt;, London, UK.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr Harput is invited to the ‘Leaders in Innovation Fellowship’ networking event, London, UK.</title>
      <link>/post/2020jan_raeng_networkingevent/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 14:03:47 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2020jan_raeng_networkingevent/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dr Harput has been invitated by Ambassador Ümit Yalçın, for “Leaders in Innovation Fellowship” networking event that he will be hosting on Tuesday, 28th January 2020 at the Ambassadorial Residence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Leaders in Innovation Fellowships (LIF) programme, which is run by the Royal Academy of Engineering and supported by the Newton Fund, works with engineers, academics and researchers in 16 countries, who have an innovation that could have a positive social or economic impact in their own countries or other developing nations. 15 participants from each country are chosen to attend an intensive 2-week entrepreneurship training course in London followed by up to a year of one-to-one support in their home countries to build their capacity to bring their innovations to market. There is a global community of over a thousand innovators working across a wide range of engineering disciplines and sectors tackling complex global challenges, including medical technology, agrotechnology and food security, water and sanitation, sustainable energy, and data infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minister of Education (United Arab Emirates) and Executive Vice President (Khalifa University) visited LSBU.</title>
      <link>/post/2020jan_uae_minister_of_education/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2020 14:03:47 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2020jan_uae_minister_of_education/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dr Harput and Dr Grisan presented thier ultrasound imaging project to HE. Hussein Bin Ibrahim Al Hammadi (Minister of Education, UAE Ministry of Education), Dr. Arif Sultan Al Hammadi (Executive Vice President, Khalifa University) and Dr. Samuel Sheng Mao Senior Director, Masdar Institute/Khalifa University.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our abstract has been accepted for the 25th European symposium on Ultrasound Contrast Imaging 2020 in Rotterdam, NL.</title>
      <link>/post/2019dec_rotterdam_conf_accept/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 14:03:47 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2019dec_rotterdam_conf_accept/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our abstract on ‘Micro vessel Analysis with 3D Super-resolution Ultrasound and Super-Resolved Velocity Mapping’ has been accepted as an oral presentation for the competition: SUPER-RESOLUTION IMAGING.
It will be presented by Dr Matthieu Toulemonde at the 25th European symposium on Ultrasound Contrast Imaging 2020 in Rotterdam, NL.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apply for a PhD in ultrasound imaging.</title>
      <link>/post/2019nov_phd_positions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 14:03:47 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2019nov_phd_positions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PhD scholarships available in ultrasound imaging: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jobs.ac.uk/job/BWO083/phd-scholarships&#34;&gt;https://www.jobs.ac.uk/job/BWO083/phd-scholarships&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lsbu.ac.uk/__data/assets/pdf_file/0011/254756/Advert-PhD-SoE_Nov2019.pdf&#34;&gt;Click here&lt;/a&gt; for more details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Attending the IEEE International Ultrasonics Symposium (IUS) 2019 in Glasgow, UK.</title>
      <link>/post/2019oct_ius/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2019 14:03:47 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2019oct_ius/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We did not forget to present our research, while catching up with friends and colleagues in Glasgow, UK.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are our proceedings:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/8926069&#34;&gt;Acoustic Wave Sparsely-Activated Localization Microscopy (AWSALM): In Vivo Fast Ultrasound Super-Resolution Imaging using Nanodroplets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/8925861&#34;&gt;Super-Resolution Ultrasound Image Filtering with Machine-Learning to Reduce the Localization Error&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/8926067&#34;&gt;Minimization of Nanodroplet Activation Time using Focused-Pulses for Droplet-Based Ultrasound Super-Resolution Imaging&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/8926179&#34;&gt;Photoacoustic Super-Resolution Imaging using Laser Activation of Low-Boiling-Point Dye-Coated Nanodroplets in vitro and in vivo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/8925892&#34;&gt;Activation and 3D Imaging of Phase-change Nanodroplet Contrast Agents with a 2D Ultrasound Probe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr Harput joins London South Bank University as a lecturer</title>
      <link>/post/2019july_lsbu_start/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jul 2019 14:03:47 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2019july_lsbu_start/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is a very friendly environment. Many opportunities to start and lead new research projects.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr Harput&#39;s leaving do at Imperial College London</title>
      <link>/post/2019july_imperial_leaving/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2019 14:03:47 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2019july_imperial_leaving/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Thank you everyone for coming. I will remember it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
